We think that in the future of tokenization kind of level everything else.
The customer could have the same rights as an important VC or the hour as someone with 100
millions of dollars and it could also give the same type of access to these companies.
Clearly, still some work in progress to be done, but I really think that's where the puck is going.
Hi everyone, welcome to Unchained, your no-hate resource for all things crypto.
I'm your host, Laura Shin. Before we get started, a quick reminder, nothing you hear on Unchained
is an investment advice. This show is for informational and entertainment purposes only and my guests
and I may hold assets discussed in the show. For more disclosures, visit UnchainedCrypto.com.
Looking to unlock your crypto's liquidity? Figure offers crypto-beft loans with an industry low
8.91% fixed rate. They're the only major provider with decentralized MPC custody
and new liquidation protection. Take out a loan at figure-markets.co/unchained.
Are you a builder who needs to add on-chain trading to your product?
The Uniswap Trading API from Uniswap Labs offers plug-and-play access to some of the
deepest liquidity in crypto. It's on-chain execution at an enterprise level.
More liquidity, less complexity. Visit hub.uniswap.org to learn more.
Today's guest is Johan Karabrod, Senior Vice President and General Manager of Robinhood Crypto.
Welcome, Johan.
Hi. Good to see you again. How are you?
Nice to see you. I'm good. Good. Glad to have you.
So, for Q3, Robinhood saw quite a boost in earnings from the year prior and crypto revenue
tripled. Why do you think crypto revenue on Robinhood grew so much year over year?
Yeah. It's been a great year. Q3 was a great quarter for us.
I think the combination of the environment that just really popped in crypto, but also all the
new features that we built around crypto, we added a lot more assets. We started to offer a
sticking in most of the states in the US, and we also focused a lot on the advanced trader.
So, I think that kind of resulted into this growth that we've seen. But really, I think it's also the
interest from the retail customers that have just grown in the past few years, and especially last year.
And Robinhood has had such a journey. I mean, if you just think like Vlad and his co-founder,
they started as young guys, not that they're old, by any stretch. But they kind of weathered
the whole storm during the meme coin, the GameStop media. And then we saw the very slick presentation
you guys did introducing a bunch of crypto products over the summer. And now, Robinhood is part of
the S&P 500. And I wondered if you could just talk about how reaching that new milestone,
if that's influenced Robinhood's plans, or at least how you think about or approach the business.
Yeah, I mean, I think there is so much to tell about this story. I think
for a lot of reason, I have a ton of respect and admiration for our funders. But I think one
thing that I often explain is the story of crypto within Ramenode. They actually decided to launch
crypto in 2018, just in the first quarter. So really, at the moment, where most companies were
actually turning their back to crypto, and they were like, it's a winter. It was past 2017 ICOs and
NFTs against Sega. And so instead of going into this direction, like everyone else, Vlad and Beiju
were like, you know what, some customer want to have access to this type of financial instrument.
They actually believe that it will be part of the next financial system of tomorrow.
And so they still decide to build on it and to offer it to the customer and to stop building.
And so I think it just shows that they have this very unique capability to understand where the
trends are going and to understand where they think that there is actual interest when everyone else
fails the opposite. But I think the success that we've seen around the recent quarter is just
a result of a lot of many years of work. Like for example, we've been building a lot of this
feature that we announced during the CAN event for multiple years. And so far as it was more of a
celebration, because finally these features are out. But we know that the job is not done at this
point. Most of the financial trading is still happening off-chain on centralized places.
And so we don't think that we are where we can be and we think there is still a lot to do. So
Vlad is someone who is really pushing us all the time. And so when the S&P announcement happened,
I'm not even sure if there was a quick slightly sage about it like progress and let's keep working
basically. So I think that's the mental model he has for himself. And I think that's what we
always aspire to do also for the company. And we want to just keep building features that people
excited about. So I am so interested to hear your thoughts on where the crypto market is headed.
Because as I'm sure you're very well aware, crypto price action has been a bit choppy.
Ever since 10/10. There are a lot of people saying we're entering a bear market. I've had
other people on my show who say that 2026 will prove that the four-year cycle is dead. They,
at least somebody from Bitwise, Ryan Rasmussen, he predicted that we would reach new all-time
highs in crypto in 2026. I was so curious for your thoughts. Do you think crypto is entering
a bear market or not? And just generally, how was Robinhood preparing for any changes in the market?
Yeah. So I always say that I'm very bad at predicting Bitcoin prices. And if I was a bit
better at it, I would probably not be working right now. So that's why I always say that. But
I think what has been interesting is to see that there is a lot of support still. It's been a few
times that Bitcoin is going in the low 80s and still rebalancing. So I think that shows that
there's still a lot of strong support. I also think that we're still seeing a lot of activity
coming in from our customers, not just on trading the actual assets, but on buying crypto, then
transferring it out to DeFi platform and doing things on DeFi. So that, to me, shows that we are
far from the bear market or at least the one that we've known in the past. And so I think so far,
what we see from our customers is that they are actually, they have a pretty long-term horizon.
They are usually a younger demographic. And so they see it more as a positive kind of opportunity.
And so our focus has been more into building the right tools for them to take advantage of this
kind of situation, especially for advanced trader. For example, just fallout new fees that if you use
automatic change writing feature, you can trade for us low as three basis points. So that's been
more for focus. And then we let the customer kind of decide if they think the price is going to go
down or up, because like I said, that wasn't very good at it. And I was wondering because
you guys have rolled out so many new crypto offerings. Obviously, we have tokenized stocks,
there's prediction markets, perps, there's just a whole bunch of new things.
And I wondered if you could just talk about the evolution of the crypto users that you have
on your platform. If you think that they've kind of evolved over time, what are they like now or
what are the different categories of them? Yeah, absolutely. I mean, we have to think
almost every segment at this point where initially a lot of customers were thinking about Robinhood
for crypto as more of a playing ground for people that were not really serious about crypto.
And they were mostly holding stock, buying a bit of exposure to Bitcoin or Ethereum.
But since then, we graduated from this place a long time ago. And we now have all the advanced
customers that I was talking about to the people that are really into no leverage with
special products to people that just want to hold. And so for them, sticking is very important so
they can get yelled on the asset that they all on the platform. And we also have a lot of people
that are active on DeFi. So we have built a self custody wide for that. And they are really
engaging with it. So I think we have all of them. What is more interesting is to see the
cross between the different products. And I think that's where Robinhood is pretty interesting being
this all in one application where you can start by investing into Bitcoin for the first time
or you can start using a prediction market or you can just go straight to equities or
opening a retirement account. So I think it's a pretty interesting platform where we're introducing
a lot of new investors to just like the investing world. And so for a lot of them, they didn't have
a retirement account until they started to trade production market and then they realized on the
app that we had this retirement account feature and then they went to it. And so it's like opening
it for a lot of customers. They are thinking about just investing in general and what is their
financial journey for the entire life. Yeah. So in a way, it's like you're trying to build
out offerings for all levels of sophistication with crypto. That's right. All levels of communication
of crypto, but also in use of type of assets. I think it's really important to start thinking about
the multi asset class. So for example, we have features on Bitcoin and East and we also have
the underlying asset. So if you're an administrator, you can actually hedge or collect premium between
the two different assets. Same thing with ETF. For example, if you want to all Bitcoin for the
long term, you can buy a Bitcoin ETF on your retirement account. So it's really about giving
all the choices and the accessibility to the customer and then the customer can decide where
they want to invest their own money. So given that you have offerings across that huge range,
I did want to ask you a little bit about how you see Robinhood in comparison to Coinbase.
I'm sure you're very well aware that tomorrow Coinbase is doing a big announcement and already
there's reports that they're going to be competing basically with Robinhood in some of the offerings
they already have, such as prediction markets, tokenized stocks, etc. So I just was curious to
hear how you think about where you're starting from, where they're starting from, and how you
compete against a competitor that is different for now, but you guys are definitely converging
on the same space, at least as how I see it. Yeah, I mean, I think it took us quite a long time to
actually build a brokerage and all the features that are around equities and to get to the level
of sophistication that you can get on Robinhood. So I'm not necessarily thinking that
tomorrow everything will be the same between the two applications, but I think the reality is that
we are going to start seeing a lot of this super app being created. And Robinhood was the first
and perfect example of the super app. And we've been very vocal that how helpful it has been for
our customer to be able to buy a stock like Microsoft or Tesla and being able to sell it and buy Bitcoin
the same day without having to transfer between different accounts. So I'm not necessarily surprised
that it's where they are going. And same thing with the production market. We've seen that it's
been one of our fastest growing business at Robinhood. We've seen a lot of enthusiasm
from our customer about it. And so obviously we do expect competition to come in and to try
to do the same thing. What I think is pretty unique of Robinhood is more around how we put
the customer at the center of everything that we're building and the way that we're designing
our tools and features, we go about doing a lot of user research, we spend a lot of time with
our customers to understand if they like the product, if they don't like it, what are the
things that are preventing them to use it? Why do they prefer something else? And through that,
we get to, I think a level of UI in UX that at this point has not been equal. And really,
I think that's what makes Robinhood unique. When you look at our credit card, for example,
a lot of people have been launching credit cards since we launched it. And if you look at the
numbers that we published, you can see that a lot of people are preferring our credit card.
And the reason for that is that we really spend a lot of time trying to understand
what people didn't like from other products. And we went with a pretty simple offering where it's
like you get three percent of cash back on more categories. And so in my head, as a customer,
for example, initially I was a bit doubtful about the credit card. And now it's like the only
quick that I use in my wallet. And I think that's the type of user focus that is really giving us
an advantage of the competition. Okay, yeah. And I did want to ask a little bit more about the
prediction markets, because as you said, they're all the rage now. And Robinhood has not only launched
prediction markets with CalSHI, but then it also recently announced that it would launch
a new futures and derivatives exchange through a joint venture with Susquehanna International Group.
And that would be for expanding its prediction markets product. So explain how this initiative
differs from what you're already doing with CalSHI. Yeah, I mean, the exchange basically
is the back end in a way. And so on the front end, like any products that we have on the platform,
we usually connect to multiple exchanges to give us either the best price or to give us more offering.
And so we were already integrated with more than one exchange. So this initially will just
give us more functionality and it will also allow us to build more products that are kind of unique
to Robinhood. But I think, you know, at the end of the day for the customer, it doesn't really matter.
But being able to add more exchanges and creating more competition will create more
pressure on prices and on the type of products that we can offer. So I think more competition
is always great for the customer. And you know, because this is now the largest, sorry, the fastest
growing area of Robinhood, I was curious, like what are you noticing in trends amongst like the users,
what types of users they are, what their behaviors are? Like, like, why do you think that it became
so popular so quickly? You know, I think there is many reasons. But the one that I think is the most
easy to explain is that it's a bit, it's giving like very advanced tools to a lot of customer that
didn't necessarily have these tools before. So for example, if you, I don't know, you wanted to
edge against AI or against a particular event, before event contracts, you could pick some
select stocks and you could decide that, you know, I'm going to go long or I'm going to
short or buy options accordingly. But you still add a lot of variation around the results because
maybe you were right and AI is a boom. But the company that you picked is actually having a bad
time because I don't know if that manufacturer or maybe one of their product line didn't work
as well. But with a prediction market, you can actually buy a contract that will actually give
you the same hedge that is in a way simpler way, just, you know, is AI going to be an important
next year or not? And so I think that gives a lot of opportunities for a lot of customers
to get their fit wet into the market. And the other aspect is just that a lot of these contracts
are closer to the actual individual. So, you know, when there is a major election contract
for a lot of customers, they can actually engage with it because there is a direct impact for them.
So I think that's the reason. And then obviously, you know, we have different categories and some
people are engaging with one category more than the other. But I think it's just a very unique
tool that gives you a lot more capabilities that until now you are not able to.
And how do you find that those users differ from others? Like, are there certain traders
on Robinhood that only like to trade prediction markets? Or do you find that there's just a lot
of crossover? And if there is a lot of crossover, is it with the crypto traders in particular?
I got to be honest with you. I don't have this data on top of my head, but you know, Robinhood is
at more than 26 million customers now, 100 pounds. So I'm sure you have like some segment of just
prediction markets and some of the doc crossing with crypto and some of the doc crossing with all
the products. So it's not to tell you just like that. And I also have to ask, I'm sure you're
very well aware that Connecticut's Consumer Protection Department issued cease and desist
orders to a whole bunch of different prediction market platforms, including Robinhood. And they
accused you and these other platforms of conducting unlicensed online gambling and sports wagering.
What's your response to that? You know, we've been working with Regret enough for a very long time
since the inception of Robinhood. And so I think there is always a lot of time that we spend with
our legal team and compliance team. And we engage a lot with the regulatory for the case
operation market with the CFTC. But in the case of crypto with the SEC, always in the ODFS in the
US. And we have multiple license across the globe. So I have full confidence in our legal team. And
overall, you know, if we launch a product, it means that we felt confident into our ability to do so.
Overall, it's a it's a moving topic. And it's a pretty hot topic that has been going on for the
past few months. And my hope is that, you know, we can avoid the same situation that we did with
crypto in the past four years and, you know, create a situation where there was starting to be almost
a bad on crypto. And then everyone was kind of leaving the United States to build on offshore to
as a user to use VPN to be able to access all this platform. And so I hope we can avoid the same
situation here. And that instead we can find the right regulatory system that everyone can contribute
to, because Robinhood knows how to work with which regulator. So if at some point there's a framework
that is in place and we can use it for more, we'll be able to adapt to it very quickly.
Okay. Yeah, so let's now talk about some of the big announcements from the summer.
And so I'm sure you're very well aware. Robinhood made huge waves when it announced that Robinhood
chain would be an L2 on Ethereum. And I wondered if you could talk about that decision. You know,
why did you decide to build an L2 on Ethereum as opposed to, for instance, deploying straight
on Solana, which had been rumored as the other plausible option? Yeah, I mean, we, we look at
multiple options. Like anything we do, we spend a lot of time comparing different options, what
could be the outcome. And we love the Solana team. We are pretty good partner. We partner in a lot
of other ways. For example, if you use a Robin wallet, we'll cover as a gas fees on Solana through
some of our partnership with them. So, you know, it's not a, we didn't decide to go with the
Ethereum L2 just because we didn't like Solana. It was more about what we were trying to achieve.
And so what we were trying to achieve is we really wanted some point to replace the traditional
finance that is still working in a very old way. And for that, we felt like we need to have
enough customization and enough ways for us to, to kind of control what we want to build on the
chain. And we didn't feel like we could do that through those our ways and having all one stack
basically. So the question was more about building our own L1 versus an L2. And the reason what we
decided to build an L2 on Ethereum was we felt like we were getting the security of the Ethereum
network for free in a way. And we could just focus on building the feature that we think
are missing for the financial system. And not have to worry about, you know, the different
decentralization aspect and security of the actual R1. And I think that's something that
we often forget because Ethereum has been running for so long and other platform have been running
for so long. But, you know, having a clearly decentralized and secure blockchain is actually
not a an easy feat and takes a lot of resources, takes a lot of investment. And so getting that
for free through Ethereum is an important important point for us.
Yeah, yeah, that makes a lot of sense. Well, I did also want to ask, you know, I think I heard
you on the Edge podcast talk about how liquidity on Ethereum was another reason that you chose to
build an L2. And I just wondered, you know, currently that's more siloed probably than I think
ideally it would be. And I wondered, you know, do you have faith that this will get resolved? Or
like, how do you think about that factor that that is currently the state of play?
Yeah, I mean, for us it definitely makes it easier being an EVM compatible chain to be able to
move equally easily between the different chain. And to your point earlier, like, around the
open competitor at Coinbase, they themselves are also on an L2 on Ethereum. And so it's helpful,
I think, for the customer at the end of the day to be able to move equally between the different
chain easily. But at the end of the day, I think our goal is really to get all this complexity
away from the customers. And the way that you can buy your start tokens on our European app,
for example, the customer doesn't even really know what is happening behind the scene. Like,
we are showing a pill that purely show it's a token and so that it's a crypto purchase,
at all the complexity on gas fees and transaction and wallet addresses and everything is taking
care for the user. And so I think that's where we're going to go in the future for everything.
Clearly, you see that there's more and more chain being created on a regular basis,
there's multiple L1 being announced. And, you know, everyone is going to want to have
also their own stable coin or at least there's a lot more stable coin now that there was five
years ago. And so I think our role as Robin is going to take away all this complexity
and make sure that we aggregate the stable coins and aggregates the right transaction process
for our customers. In that way, the customer can just focus on what they are trying to achieve,
which is, I don't know, bang stocks or something like that. And not have to worry about anything
around the crypto technology behind it. So I also wanted to ask about perps because they were
obviously also a big part of the, you know, boost in revenue in Q3 and the crypto, you know,
vertical in Robinhood. And I think right now they're just in the EU and I was wondering if you,
you know, could give us a preview of when they might be expanded to other jurisdictions.
Yeah, I mean, we've said it before, like we would love the perps to be ready
to launch in the US. Clearly, we have the technology. It's running in the EU.
But currently perps, as it is, can are not allowed through CFTC. So there are some equivalent
or attempt to be equivalent to perps that are starting to exist.
Like the Coinbase one? Yeah, like the Coinbase one, which is more or less of a long-dated future.
And so we have some options available already on the platform. Like we have long-dated
share as well on some of the assets. But the true verbs, the same way that we have in the EU or
that you can find on a different platform, are still not allowed. But in the EU, it's something
that we've seen a lot of stickiness, like our customer, really liking it. I think they also
like the UIs that we built. I don't know if you've seen it, but it's like this cool letter that
you can take profit or your stop loss very easily. And you can change margins fairly easily as well.
We're pretty confident that it's a product that people would love here in the US. So
hopefully we can get the regulators to approve it quickly.
And I noticed that you guys had invested also in LiDAR's recent fundraise of $68 million.
And obviously this is just easily one of the hottest, you know,
verticals that we've seen in crypto in the last year with hyper liquid kind of kicking the whole
thing off. But I was curious, like why is it that Robinhood chose LiDAR out of all the different
contenders in the DeFi perp space? Many, many reasons. We know the LiDAR team for a very long time.
We've been working with them on and off for a long time as well. And we felt like
we liked a lot of what they've built. They also using the automation proof for a lot of their
system. And, you know, I also felt like during the 10/10 situation, they were actually handling
all the situation pretty well. And so we think it's a great team. We think the product is good.
And we wanted to be part of that journey. I think for us, it's also giving us functionality
if we want to do more into DeFi and into perps. And so it's pretty important as a business to
have options. So yeah, that's why we did it. And so can you just expound on that a little bit?
Is it something where like LiDAR might power kind of something on the back end in a DeFi way?
And then Robinhood might be the user interface or something like that? Yeah, for example,
that's something we could do, especially since we have a self custody wallet that already connects
to taxes and already connects to any kind of app that you can use on DeFi. So that's something that
you could see, for example, the wallet having a perps of foreign through it and LiDAR being
one or the only one platform that is connected to. But at this point, like, there was no
set plan. And that's why I was talking about this optionality. Like, I think when we really get
excited about the technology and when we really like how teams are working, it's when Robinhood
started thinking about potentially investing in these teams and getting an option in the future
to do more work with them. Okay. And you mentioned the 10, 10 liquidations. And I just had to ask,
obviously that does look like a sort of watershed moment, not maybe not in a positive way for
crypto. And just because you are familiar with trading infrastructure and all the things that
can go wrong in that type of world, I wonder, when you looked at what happened that day,
what do you think the industry could improve or what were your thoughts on why things went so wrong?
Yeah, it's hard to say exactly. I think we're still not too convinced by some of the explanation
that we're published. But I think overall for the industry, it's more about building resiliency,
making sure that we drive single point of value or the same way that we're building all technical
system in this kind of mindset where we want to make sure that if one system is down, we can rely
on another system. In that case, there was this problem and there was making sure that
a price, you will have multiple feeds to make sure that you don't just look at one price feed.
But at the end of the day, a lot of this platform also brand new. And so I think it is to be expected
that you will see some of these problems. I also think it's critical for the institution that
are getting into this platform to make sure that it not puts all the eggs in the same basket and to
also think about diversify things about looking at your diligence and these kind of things. But
overall, I think for the industry, it's just one of these bad moments where it's eroding a bit
the trust of not just institution but the retail customers. And usually what we see is that people
are taking a bit of a breeze there from the markets and coming back to it a bit later in the year.
And we've seen that multiple times. There was the FTX moment, obviously, not so far ago,
where it really took us a few months before people really started to reengage again.
And I think for a lot of the teams that are on Defy and the decentralized exchanges,
they are all a very good team and very strong engineering forces. But sometimes we are building
fast. Sometimes the leverage is maybe very high and too high for some instances. And that's where
we need to be careful. Alright, so in a moment, we're going to talk about some of the other things
that Robin had been doing in the crypto space. But first, we're going to take a quick word from
the sponsors make this show possible. Today's episode is sponsored by Figure, which is transforming
financial services using blockchain. They're the largest non-bank mortgage lender in the US,
with over $19 billion unlocked on their lending platform. Now, they're offering industry-low
crypto-backed loans at 8.91% interest rates at 50% LTV for BTC, ETH, and Sol. They differentiate
themselves by offering decentralized MPC custody, which protects your crypto ownership in a segregated
wallet. They've also recently launched Liquidation Protection to protect you from liquidation during
large price drops. Whether you're funding a major purchase, investing, or even buying more Bitcoin,
Figure makes it transparent. Visit figuremarkets.co/unchained to take advantage of their crypto-backed
loans today. Hey, founders and developers, if you're looking to bring on-chain trading to your
product, wallet, or platform, check out the new Uniswap Trading API from Uniswap Labs.
It's your plug-and-play gateway to global on-chain liquidity, no deep crypto experience required,
and no need to manage complex integrations or ongoing maintenance. With the Uniswap Trading
API, you'll get enterprise-grade on-chain execution, combining both on-chain and off-chain sources
for the most competitive prices. Simply put, more liquidity, less complexity. And this isn't just
any API. It connects directly to the Uniswap protocol, which has securely processed over $3.3
trillion in total volume with zero hacks. So stop worrying about liquidity infrastructure and focus
on building your product. Get access to the same liquidity that powers billions and swaps
through one powerful API. Visit hub.uniswap.org to learn more. Back to my conversation with Johan.
So the other big announcement that Robinhood had this past summer was that you launched
tokenized stocks. And this really feels like it would be at the sweet spot of all of Robinhood's
offerings and its history and its expertise. And I heard that now you're at the stage of having
1,000 stock tokens available to European customers. I wonder if you could talk a little bit about
how you managed to grow that number so quickly, and also the regulatory aspect, because obviously
people probably remember there was a little bit of a kerfuffle with opening eye right after the
launch. So yeah, just talk a little bit about those issues and how you managed to get that growing
so quickly. Yeah, I mean, so there's two different products. There is public stock token that we
launched. And to your point, we are at more than a thousand now. So what was exciting for us was
really to build the tokenization engine ourselves so that we could actually support these rapid
growths. And the engine actually can work for any type of asset. So we started with public stock
for US markets and US ETF. But in the future, we can expand to any other market, the European,
the Asian, or we could also go to any type of real world assets like real estate or arts.
So I think that's kind of the one to it we're very excited about. The second item that you
mentioned is private stock. And so the reason why we really want to do something on private is
because we feel like it's still one of this big gaps that there is between the
ultra high net worth individual and the normal kind of people that don't have multiple million in the
bank. And so we want to find a way where we can tokenize the private equity from some of these
companies, put it on shame and give access to customers. But the launch that put it in the EU
was a giveaway. So it was a one-time thing for open AI and space ads. But the vision is a lot
wider than that. We think that customer can actually access to private equity firms,
but we also think that private equity firms could stop raising money through blockchain
technology instead of having to go through the classic VC structure and then going to have a
banker and then going to go public and paying all these exchange fees. So I think that's kind
of the idea behind it. The problem is that for a lot of this private company, if they are really
hot or really in demand, they don't really need to have this raising capital problem. And so they
don't necessarily want to deal with retail. And we still think that it's not necessarily fair,
right? Like a lot of the retail customers that are using the products are the reason why the
company is actually valuable. And so we think that in the future tokenization can level everything
else. The customer could have the same right as an important VC or someone with hundred millions
of dollars and it could also give the same type of access to these companies. Clearly still some
work in progress to be done. But I really think that's where the buck is going.
And so let's just focus on the public company side. Is the kind of impetus to take the US stock
market, which is not necessarily accessible to other geographies and give people price exposure
to that? And so you wouldn't have tokenized US stocks available to US customers. Is that
the thinking? Currently not. I mean, that's why we launched into you because we didn't really
have a poor courage there and we'd have a running Robin Hood with millions of customers there.
But I think in the future you're going to start saying blockchain being developed more and more
in the US. You already have a lot of exchanges talking about modernizing their stock or using
blockchain. You have the DCs explaining how they are going to start using blockchain. And so it's
more about how do we connect all this system together so that in the US you can have 24/7
or you can have an instant settlement and not wait a day. And when it's necessary and we have to
use blockchain for it to have access to these benefits, we will definitely do it. But right now
for the largest impact we felt like the EU was a better playing ground for launching this product
and seeing really the impact there. And there's a lot of countries in the EU or even in the world
where it's still difficult for you to open a US or a larger ground and it's still difficult to
cool out your local currency into the US dollar to be able to invest. So the product we launched as
zero spread, zero p5, zero fee, we just charge the effects from euro to dollar at 10 basis point.
And so we are really trying to create a competing product that gives you a lot of advantage to
get into the space. Okay. And then so for the private equity or private, I guess, stock side,
I know, so I guess initially you guys were given some or you had access to some tokens that you
used to, sorry, to some equity that you used to make those tokens. So in the future, like,
yeah, how do you plan to expand that? And do you feel like this is something now companies
that are private will just come to expect that there will be interest in trading equity in them
in this way? I think so. And I think it's something that it's a bit of a cultural shift that will
need to happen. And the same way that if you think about it, it took us at least like five years to
get the idea of stable coin being as a real as a dollar, you know, for a very long time, people
were not sure. And you can still trade a stable coin under the dollar in some places. So they
still spread. And so it took like a bit of time for people to understand the value of the stable
coin. And same thing with retail trading for a very long time, bankers will recommend companies
like going public to not allocate to retail or to only allocate to ultra high net worth or high net
worth individuals, but mostly to just give it to institution. And slowly you're starting to see
things changing. Some of the recent big IPOs, for example, I've given a lot more to retail
and one that was public about it, bullish claim that they allocated 20% to retail, which I think
really shows the transformation from a few years ago. And so I think it's going to be the same thing
for private equity. A lot of companies don't want to deal with the pressure of having the asset
trade outside. But there are also ways to go around it that could remove the noise for the
companies, but still give access to the retail investor. And at the same time for the company
it will be beneficial because they will be able to raise capital more easily. And at lower cost,
because they will be less intelligent in the between. So I think you're going to see that
developing is just, we are at the very beginning, we're at day zero of this journey. But I'm pretty
sure that if we talk again in a couple of years, you will just be the norm to invest in some of
the square companies. And so I'm sorry. So for like, when they do IPO, do you feel like
the holders of the tokenized equity, will they, it's just like giving more access to them so that
they can kind of like take advantage of the IPO? But then also, do you think it could potentially
change IPOs in some fashion? I mean, you could see a world where there's just no more IPO,
basically, it's just you don't have to go to this process where you have to pay an exchange and a
lot of bankers and all these things. But even outside of that, I think it's more about being
able to have this access to customer and now able to write to write the the course of the company.
And so instead of waiting to invest in, you know, any company when they are going public,
basically being at the highest, a higher valuation since creation, they can invest in the seed
stage or the sales, a stage or, you know, PCD. And I just think it's, it's just a more fair system
for a lot of these customers, like instead of having to wait for the company to be public,
you can actually invest in it if you're excited by it because you, you're building an AI or you
build it in the tool that you're using on your computer. You should be able to access it at the
beginning of the launch instead. Okay, so I heard you also, I mean, you even mentioned it briefly
here, but I also heard you talk about this a little bit on the Edge podcast about tokenizing,
you know, all kinds of other things, including things like art and real estate. And that was
interesting because those concerned physical objects, you know, things that aren't as kind of
inherently digital as crypto or even stocks. And I just want to hear you talk a little bit more
about what that looks like. And do you actually see Robinhood getting into those markets? Because
it feels like it would just take a whole new apparatus at the company for even for a single one of them.
Yeah, I mean, look, I think the companies were really good at creating new businesses. Like
we were talking about production market earlier, you know, it was not something that we were doing
until we decided launch it. And so I think we are just, you know, Vlad and Biju are great founders.
I've kind of created a business for ownership spirit within the company where a lot of team
are studying from scratch and building product from scratch. So I wouldn't say that it's a limiting
factor. Usually, or limiting factor is more about customer demand and what are people really interested
in. And I think tokenization of something like real estate or art actually give accessibility to a
lot of these cameras to things that they are not necessarily able to access otherwise. You know,
being able to buy, I don't know, the apartment in New York is difficult. And so for you to be
exposed to the growth of New York as a city, you don't necessarily have a ton of ways you have
obviously rates and some ETF or some start will be linked somehow to the growth of the city.
But it's not the same as owning a piece of an apartment. And so there are different companies
that have done this kind of things in some ways. You know, they will create a fund. The fund will
buy the underlying property or the underlying piece of art. But usually the issue is that you
still have a lot of middlemen, you still have a lot of fees that are being passed to the customers.
And so it's hard to justify the return on investment. And so that's where tokenization can be helpful
where, you know, you buy a piece of property, be divided by X tokens and people can have a portion
of an apartment in New York or painting. So I think it's definitely possible. The question is
more about customer demand. How do you manage the physical location and the tokens and how do you
make sure that you tie them together correctly? But, you know, we meet a lot of startups that are
working in this space. And the progress that we've seen in the past has been very exciting. And so
I definitely think it's something that we will see in the future. Like as of one of the next
type of asset that people will start tokenizing. The question for launching that Robin will be
more on do our customer care about it and because they want to have access to it. And if they do,
we will definitely build it. But if they don't, we can focus on something else.
Yeah, I honestly, initially, I wasn't thinking about the investment piece. And I was literally
thinking about like tokenizing a deed, but then you also have to transfer the house. So that
that actually seems much more up Robinhood's alley. I did also just want to ask, you know,
what you were talking about about how this technology just enables, you know, a lot of a lot of new
things. And one thing I think you briefly touched on was just like, you know, settlement can happen
a lot more quickly or be like basically instantaneous. I just wondered if you could talk a little bit
more about how as crypto becomes more adopted as this technology, you know, kind of powers a lot of
backends and gets integrated in more of finance. I wondered what you thought that would unlock
for users? Like how would it impact their financial lives? Yeah, I mean, there are a few things where
basically because of the settlement being delayed by business days, you, a lot of companies need to
lock capital. And so that capital doesn't work, doesn't generate yield. And therefore, that's
one of the costs. And so the cost sometimes it's passed to the customer or sometimes it's just passed
on the underlying asset. But overall, you know, that that could help the other thing that I often
explained to customer that I don't know if you've tried to transfer a brokerage account to another
days with this process called ECAT, where you basically fight a form and you wait three to five days,
sometimes more. And you don't really know what's happening, but sometimes it's transferred correctly,
sometimes you're missing assets, sometimes you're missing cost basis. All of this is very
funky, frankly. And so having the tokenization of this asset can just make it instant and you have
all the information transferred because it's, you know, in the contracts. And so I think overall,
that's kind of where we're going to see for customer, it's going to give more functionality,
it's going to increase competition because a lot of people can trade using the same technology.
And therefore, you should start to see a world where you also reduce the cost and
customers should be able to trade for the work cost at the end of the day.
All right. So I did also want to ask, Robin Hood is famously one of the best product companies.
And I'm sure you're very well aware that crypto maybe could use some help in this area.
And I wonder, you know, when you look at some of the different crypto offerings or just kind of
where crypto is in its development, how do you think about what crypto needs in order to make
itself more accessible to mainstream users? Yeah, I mean, I think that's something that I often
talk about is, I always think that crypto was made by engineer for engineer. We forgot 99% of
the population at the same time. And sometimes what I recommend to fund there is to actually stop
talking about crypto, you know, and to focus about what are you trying to launch? What is the product
you're trying to build? And, you know, if it's using crypto rails and it's working well in the
other hood, that's great. But otherwise, just don't talk about it. And let's focus less about
the protocol and more about the actual use case that you're trying to develop. And I think that's
what we've been trying to do with some of the product we launched recently. And, you know, I
told you before, like, for stock tokens, like, we don't explain which layer to is or how it's working
with the gas fees and all these things, we just tell you like, buy the this last token, you buy it.
And it's like the same experience that if you were buying it on the on the US coverage. And I think
that's really key for follows to succeed as a as a committee is to focus less about what is going on
under the hood, the same way that I'm sure that when you're using your phone and you're texting
your friend, you don't really know what's the protocol happening behind the scenes. And is it
using RCA or is it using something else? You just send a text. And so I think that's what we need to
do for for crypto. And that's what we need to focus on. So I did also want to then ask you,
because you we've kind of talked around this a little bit, or you hinted at this,
it does feel like, and already we're seeing that Coinbase is doing a little bit of this,
it does look like Robin Hood could use DeFi a lot more than it already is. And obviously, you know,
you have the Robin Hood chain. And so potentially, this is probably what some of your plans are for
that. But I wondered if you could just talk about how you think Robin Hood could use more of DeFi
or what it would look like to have the two become kind of more combined.
Yeah, I mean, I think the the world where, you know, DeFi really develops will actually,
you'll see a lot of for interaction that we have on the platform that are currently centralized
that could actually happen on DeFi. And I think a lot of the assets, the new asset that we've been
talking about will will exist on DeFi as well. So it's more a question of when versus if I will
say right now, I don't think we we have the technology set up yet. That's why we're building
our chain. And that's why we're building all the compliance tool within it. But once it's going
to be live, I think you will see more and more for systems starting to use it. Because you can do
a lot more on DeFi than just trading assets, you can also create a system to verify and
identify customers, make sure that, you know, the wallet that is interacting with our system is
the same one as it was like a week ago and not someone else spoofing it. So a lot of that can be
billed. I just think we're at the beginning to be honest. And I do have to ask about one other
offering that we know that Coinbase has that potentially maybe Robinhood might be thinking about,
I don't know. But, you know, they acquired Echo, which is a token launchpad. And I wondered if
Robinhood is thinking of doing any kind of ICO type product. You know, at this point, I think for us,
we're more in the concept of listing what our customer are really asking for and less about
telling customer what to invest in. And so I think for now, we are feeling pretty good about
how quickly we've been able to list assets that our customer have been wanting.
And, you know, we will see. But frankly, we have a very similar product called IPO Access before.
And we think that it's not very hard to duplicate it if we wanted to.
But overall, I will say that, you know, I want to see a bit more what is going to happen in the
space before we we stop launching into our customer. Yeah, yeah. Clearly that that area is,
yeah, I think it's undergoing a change of some sort, maybe, is how to put it.
Okay, I did also want to ask about the recent news that Robinhood is buying the Indonesian
brokerage PT Bwana Capital Securitas and another company, they're a crypto trading company, PT
Pentagon, I think, asset crypto. And, you know, now with like all your offerings in Europe,
I just wondered if you could talk a little bit about why you chose Indonesia and how you think
generally about international expansion? Yeah, I mean, international expansion is one of our key
pillar. We've been pretty open about it and clear about it. So, you know, we require an exchange
called Bitstep in Europe. They have licenses a bit across the globe. We also announced the
acquisition of WonderFi in Canada. And we are live in the UK in multiple forms. So, you know, for
us, international is definitely something that we want to push on. In Asia, we are currently live
on the Bitstep side in Singapore. And so, for us, it was like one big region. But if you think about
crypto in Southeast Asia, Indonesia is one of the population that is the most excited about crypto
and engaged about crypto. So, that's why we want to get this acquisition done. It's giving us the
functionality to launch there. And, you know, to be able to enter market to this very, to finally.
But I think at the end of the day, for us, like you shouldn't be surprised if you see
this announcement because it's a really part of this pillar that we say that we wanted to
have Robinhood basically offering any type of financial instrument that you were interested in
and available globally everywhere in the planet. So, we have some work to do there.
Yeah, I actually lived in Indonesia right after I graduated from college. So, I have a soft spot
for it in my heart. It's a special country. Okay. So, I want to go back to something you
mentioned earlier, which is, you know, talk about like Robinhood's future as a super app.
Just describe a little bit more like what that looks like and how you see, you know,
some of the different themes that we talked about in this episode playing a part, you know,
like tokenization or just, you know, crypto generally.
Well, you know, we also announced a few more things like banking. For example,
we started to write out to customer. And so, you can see that slowly, we are trying to get
all the pillar of your financial ecosystem. And I think the question between the different
products will just become more and more intertwined with the evolution of regulation and the technology
as well. You can see a world where, you know, the brokerage is using a lot more of the blockchain
technology. You can see a world where we are tokenizing more and more of the brokerage and
all the products that we offer. And I think that's really the benefits we are getting from
having one company that is specialized in all these different financial elements. But
there is still a lot of work to be done. And especially in the US, we also have a lot of
work to be done on the regulation side. You know, we are still waiting on the market structure bill,
for example, that should really help define some of these elements and tell us what we can do or not.
And so, I think it's maybe a little too early to tell you exactly how this is going to happen.
Okay. Okay. Well, last question. For 2026, do you have any crypto prediction that you would feel
comfortable making? Any prediction? I think what I would be
excited about is to see how production market and crypto are going to until twice and even more.
You already see it. You know, a lot of production markets are using crypto technology, but you
don't see yet a lot of them using crypto in between. So for example, if you invest in a very long-term
contract, your capital is a lot. So I think it could be interesting to see how people are going
to start using crypto to find a way to reminerate the time that you're spending on the contract.
So yeah, that's probably the prediction. And the second one I always think about more is AI
and crypto is a too big thing that's all happening. And we haven't seen yet the cross that we were
thinking will happen a lot sooner, like around lending GPUs or reminorating GPUs and all these
things. So excited to see if 2026 is going to be the year finally.
Okay, that wasn't the last question because now I have a follow-up question, which is just
for the prediction market line, turning the assets that you've put into any one bet into
a productive asset. What do you think that could look like?
I'm not sure yet, but I think it's something that we definitely need to start thinking about,
especially if you want to encourage more and more of people to invest in the long-term and not just
the thing happening in the real time, basically.
Okay, okay. Well, yeah, that sounds really interesting to me. So I hope to see that happen.
Johan, it's been a pleasure as usual. Thank you so much for coming on Unchained.
Unchained is produced by Laura Shin with help from Matt Pilchard,
Juan Oranovich, Margaret Curia and Pam Majumdar. Thanks for listening.